<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	type="LoopStart" icon="loop_start_kafka.png">
	<name>Kafka Consumer Loop Start</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows to iteratively poll batches of messages from Kafka and to process them.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		In each iteration another batch of messages is consumed from Kafka and processed.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Client ID">
				An id string to pass to the server when making requests. The purpose of this is to
				be able to track the source of requests beyond just ip/port by allowing a logical
				application name to be included in server-side request logging.
			</option>
			<option name="Group ID">
				A unique string that identifies the consumer group this consumer belongs to. 
			</option>
			<option name="Topics">
				<p>
				A pattern or list of topics the consumer has to subscribe to.
				</p>
				<p>
				A pattern has to be a regular expression as defined 
				<a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html">here</a>.
				The topics list has to be in the form <tt>topic1,topic2,...</tt>.
				</p>
			</option>
			<option name="Topic is pattern">
				If this option is selected, the value of topics will be treated as a pattern, and
				as a list otherwise.
			</option>
			<option name="Append topic column">
				If this option is selected, an additional column is added to the output table
				containing information about the name of the topic the message/row originates
				from.
			</option>
			<option name="Batch size">
				The size of each batch, i.e., number of rows in the output table.
			</option>
			<option name="Stop Execution">
				Determines how to stop the execution of this node.
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Never</b> Ensures that the loop execution never
						stops. 
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Once message queue is empty</b> Stops the execution once there
						are no new messages available
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Poll timeout (ms)">
				The time, in milliseconds, spent waiting in poll request if data is not immediately available.
			</option>
			<option name="Convert message to JSON">
				If this option is selected the consumed messages are converted from String
				to JSON.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<option name="Advanced Settings">
				Allows to specify additional consumer related options, e.g., poll interval
				and session timeout.  For further details on the individual options
				see the tooltip or consult the official
				<a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/">Kafka documentation</a>.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Kafka connection">Connection details used to create the Kafka Consumer
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Batched Kafka messages">The current batch of consumed Kafka messages
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>