<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	type="Source" icon="kafka_consumer.png">
	<name>Kafka Consumer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows to consume messages from Kafka.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node allows to consume messages from Kafka for given topics and to
			store them in a table.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Client ID">
				An id string to pass to the server when making requests. The purpose of this is to
				be able to track the source of requests beyond just ip/port by allowing a logical
				application name to be included in server-side request logging.
			</option>
			<option name="Group ID">
				A unique string that identifies the consumer group this consumer belongs to. 
			</option>
			<option name="Poll timeout (ms)">
				The time, in milliseconds, spent waiting in poll if data is not available in the buffer.
	            If 0, returns immediately with any records that are currently available in the buffer.
			</option>
			<option name="Max number of messages per poll">
				The maximum number of messages polled in a single request. 
			</option>
			<option name="Max empty polls (-1 for infinite)">
				<p>
				Defines after how many successive empty polls the node is allowed to finish its execution.
				<br/>
				If the value is set to -1, which is only allowed if this node is executed in
				streaming-mode, the consumer will indefinitely poll messages.
				</p>
				<p>
				If the values is set to -1 the relevant timeouts should be adapted in order to
				reduce overhead due to re-connecting and rebalancing.
				</p>
			</option>
			<option name="Topics">
				<p>
				A pattern or list of topics the consumer has to subscribe to.
				</p>
				<p>
				A pattern has to be a regular expression as defined 
				<a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html">here</a>.
				The topics list has to be in the form <tt>topic1,topic2,...</tt>.
				</p>
			</option>
			<option name="Topic is pattern">
				If this option is selected, the value of topics will be treated as a pattern, and
				as a list otherwise.
			</option>
			<option name="Append topic column">
				If this option is selected, an additional column is added to the output table
				containing information about the name of the topic the message/row originates
				from.
			</option>
			<option name="Convert message to JSON">
				If this option is selected the consumed messages are converted from String
				to JSON.
			</option>
			<option name="Ignore history">
				Automatically skips all unprocessed messages. 
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<option name="Advanced Settings">
				Allows to specify additional consumer related options, e.g., poll interval
				and session timeout.				.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Kafka connection">Connection details used to create the Kafka Consumer
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Data table">Data table storing all the consumed messages
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>