<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	type="Source" icon="kafka_consumer.png">
	<name>Kafka Consumer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows to consume messages from Kafka.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node allows to consume messages from a Kafka cluster for given topics and to
			store them in a table.
			<br/>
			<i>Note:</i> Offsets are committed at the end of the nodes execution as well
			as whenever the partitions become reassigned.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Client ID">
				An id string to pass to the Kafka cluster when making requests.
				This string can be included as a logical application name in server-side request logging,
				thus making it easier to track the source of requests beyond ip/port.
			</option>
			<option name="Group ID">
				A unique string that identifies the consumer group this consumer belongs to. 
			</option>
			<option name="Topic(s)">
				<p>
				A pattern or list of topics the consumer subscribes to.
				</p>
				<p>
				A pattern has to be a regular expression as defined 
				<a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html">here</a>.
				The topics list has to be entered in the form <tt>topic1,topic2,...</tt>.
				</p>
			</option>
			<option name="Topic is pattern">
				If this option is selected, the value of topics will be treated as a pattern instead of a list.
			</option>
			<option name="Append message info columns">
				If this option is selected,  additional columns are added to the output table
				containing detailed information about the message/row. More precisely the
				following columns are added: <tt>Topic, Partition, Offset, Message creation date</tt>.
			</option>
			<option name="Convert message to JSON">
				If this option is selected, the consumed messages are converted from String
				to JSON.
			</option>
			<option name="Max number of messages per poll">
				The maximum number of messages polled in a single request. 
			</option>
			<option name="Poll timeout (ms)">
				The time, in milliseconds, spent waiting for messages in a poll request.
			</option>
			<option name="Stop Criterion">
				Determines how to stop the execution of this node.
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Stop when number of consumed messages exceeds</b> This node will stop once no more messages 
						are available, but at the latest after the specified number of messages were consumed.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Stop when message timestamp exceeds</b> Consumes all messages created up until the
						selected date &amp; time. If the selected date &amp; time is in the future, the 
						execution stops once a poll request returns no messages.
						<br/>
						Selecting &lt;Use execution date &amp; time&gt; consumes all 
						messages up until the date &amp; time the node is executed. The &lt;Current time&gt;
						button sets the date &amp; time to the current local time.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<option name="Advanced Settings">
				Allows to specify additional consumer related options, e.g., poll interval
				and session timeout.  For further details on the individual options
				see the tooltip or consult the official
				<a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/">Kafka documentation</a>.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Kafka connection">Connection details used to create the Kafka Consumer
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Data table">Data table storing all the consumed messages
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>